<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jason&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 09:48:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Condrocet&#39;s Paradox in Political Science (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/condrocetcycles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/condrocetcycles/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Condorcet Paradox&amp;rdquo; in political science observes that even if the preferences of all the individuals in some society are &amp;ldquo;rational&amp;rdquo;, the preferences of the group may not be1. Furthermore, the probability that irrational group preferences arise increase as the number of voters and number of policies under consideration become large.
I thought this result was rather unintuitive. After all, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of voting if group preferences are inconsistent a lot of the time?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Politics Review</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/analyzepoliticsreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:08:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/analyzepoliticsreview/</guid>
      <description>General Impressions Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a book called &amp;ldquo;Analyzing Politics&amp;rdquo; by Kenneth A Shepsle, which introduces rational models in political science. Rational models seek to explain political behavior (e.g. group voting, legislation, etc.) using individuals with &amp;ldquo;rational preferences&amp;rdquo;. Because I&amp;rsquo;ve waded through an economics major, I felt at home with this book&amp;rsquo;s treatment of the subject. My next few blog posts will cover a few topics I found interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi Everyone! I&amp;rsquo;m Jason Yang, a 4th year Economics Major and Math Minor at the University of Chicago.
I&amp;rsquo;ve produced some (probably mediocre) research in Financial Economics as an Undergrad and currently love reading interesting articles published on the American Economic Review, Journal of Political Economy, and Journal of Finance.
Coffee is my big hobby; I currently roast and brew single origin coffees from around the world.
About the Blog I have the blog divided by Category and Tag</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Ethiopia Yirgacheffe</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_3_18_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_3_18_21/</guid>
      <description>I was surprised to find a bag of beans from Ethiopia Yirgacheffe roasted yesterday at a local roastery (Kusanya Cafe) at Whole Foods. The beans had a very smooth mouthfeel and were very bright and fruity.
I tried V60 first with the tabbed &amp;amp; bleached paper filters. The coffee felt quite thin but definitely not lacking in personality.
The Clever Dripper with a cloth filter tasted similar but had a much fuller body (which I personally prefer) because of the additional dissolved oils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nesco Roasting Guide and Review</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</guid>
      <description>I got a great deal on a Nesco roaster ($45 for an open-box product, normally $80) and figured it would be great value at that price. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this roaster ~50 times, which should be enough to comment a bit on a very simple machine.
I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post as I collect more data and learn new things about the roaster.
Pricing If you want to buy a Nesco, you probably won&amp;rsquo;t have to buy it at full price ($80).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
