<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jason&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 09:48:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Tasting between 3 more coffees and Setup Update</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_6_18_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_6_18_22/</guid>
      <description>Coffee Tasting I&amp;rsquo;m once again stuck with 3 different mostly-full bags of coffee (basically 2+ months supply) going stale and losing value day by day. Might as well do a comparative tasting!
I tried 3 different coffees today
 Ethiopian Single Origin from Counter Culture Rwandan Single Origin from Partner&amp;rsquo;s Coffee Costa Rica Single Origin from Peet&amp;rsquo;s Coffee  They&amp;rsquo;re all supposedly light roasts, although the Peet&amp;rsquo;s coffee was clearly a medium or medium-dark by comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I&#39;m thinking about Coinbase Stock</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coinbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 10:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coinbase/</guid>
      <description>How the business works Coinbase has several lines of business with the goal of creating a crypto personal finance ecosystem (payments, investment, loans, credit, and a bunch more). I&amp;rsquo;m primarly interested in the trading part of the business, which makes about 80-90% of their revenue.
At a high level, coinbase trading revenue is Revenue = RetailTransactionVolume * Fees
Their costs are in line with any other growthy tech business - lots of tech investment to build out the platform and lots of sales and marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Delayed 2022 Single Origin List</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coffeelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coffeelist/</guid>
      <description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to build my palate so I can identify differences across single origin coffees. So here&amp;rsquo;s my list so far:
 Colombia Brazil (Dry Process) Guatemala Huehuetenago / Antigua Burundi Ethiopia (Washed, Natural) Sumatra Peru India Bali Honduras  I pulled this list from some combination of Sweet Maria&amp;rsquo;s (a site that ships unroasted coffee) most popular list and the most common origins I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on coffee roaster websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investor Beliefs and Asset Pricing</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/thesis/</guid>
      <description>In my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s honors thesis, I find that pessimism and disagreement increase during economic crises, that the average investor predicts returns very poorly, and that the data rejects a belief-driven CAPM model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Portfolio Choice</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/portfolioselection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/portfolioselection/</guid>
      <description>Some of you might be interested in what finance theory has to say about saving and investing. In this post I’ll cover a classic model for portfolio choice and what we can learn from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I bought the Breville Dual Boiler</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/favoritecoffees_3_12_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/favoritecoffees_3_12_22/</guid>
      <description>These two points are more indicative of my personal preference and situation, more than anything else.
There were 2 main drivers for me:
 Consistency and ease of use Fast heat up time  Consistency and ease of use go hand in hand. The dial-in process requires a ton of time, effort, and (now increasingly expensive&amp;hellip;) coffee. Ideally, you dial-in like a science experiment - change one variable and evaluate the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Tasting between 3 Coffees</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_1_9_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_1_9_22/</guid>
      <description>Since my Nesco roaster was recalled (funny story for another time), I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to own 3 different fresh(ish) coffees at once until just today.
Onto business - I tried 3 different coffees.
 Ethiopian Single Origin coffee from Shearwater Coffee in Westport, CT Highline Blend (a light roast blend, couldn&amp;rsquo;t find origin info) from Irving Farm in New York, NY Decaf Guatemala from Happy Mug in Edinboro, PA  I looked for the predominant flavor, finish, and texture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Unrigorous Pitch for Some Cryptos</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/cryptopitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/cryptopitch/</guid>
      <description>TLDR  Crypto is popular Investors can get high returns by lending out cryptocurrencies, but they take on credit risk and currency risk. Everyday people have no shot of accessing that risk because they don’t own commercial banks. So, this form of lending may have a minor role in diversifying an investment portfolio.  There’s a lot of buzz on crypto. News: commonly read finance news like Bloomberg now reports Crypto as its own section</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best United Miles Redemption Ever? (&#43; bonus rant)</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/unitedpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/unitedpoints/</guid>
      <description>Best United Miles Redemption Ever? (+ bonus rant) | Jason&#39;s Blogvar doNotTrack=!1;doNotTrack||(window.ga=window.ga||function(){(ga.q=ga.q||[]).push(arguments)},ga.l=+new Date,ga(&#39;create&#39;,&#39;UA-123-45&#39;,&#39;auto&#39;),ga(&#39;send&#39;,&#39;pageview&#39;)){&#34;@context&#34;:&#34;https://schema.org&#34;,&#34;@type&#34;:&#34;BreadcrumbList&#34;,&#34;itemListElement&#34;:[{&#34;@type&#34;:&#34;ListItem&#34;,&#34;position&#34;:1,&#34;name&#34;:&#34;Posts&#34;,&#34;item&#34;:&#34;https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/&#34;},{&#34;@type&#34;:&#34;ListItem&#34;,&#34;position&#34;:2,&#34;name&#34;:&#34;Best United Miles Redemption Ever? (+ bonus rant)&#34;,&#34;item&#34;:&#34;https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/unitedpoints/&#34;}]}{&#34;@context&#34;:&#34;https://schema.org&#34;,&#34;@type&#34;:&#34;BlogPosting&#34;,&#34;headline&#34;:&#34;Best United Miles Redemption Ever? (+ bonus rant)&#34;,&#34;name&#34;:&#34;Best United Miles Redemption Ever? (\u002b bonus rant)&#34;,&#34;description&#34;:&#34;Credit card blogs love to recommend buying first class flights abroad to get the most \u0026amp;lsquo;value\u0026amp;rsquo; out of your points, citing 2 to 5 cents per point in some cases.\nI think …&#34;,&#34;keywords&#34;:[&#34;PersonalFinance&#34;],&#34;articleBody&#34;:&#34;Credit card blogs love to recommend buying first class flights abroad to get the most ‘value’ out of your points, citing 2 to 5 cents per point in some cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nesco Review</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</guid>
      <description>I got a great deal on a Nesco roaster ($45 for an open-box product, normally $80) and figured it would be great value at that price. I’ve used this roaster ~50 times, which should be enough to comment a bit on a very simple machine.
I’ll update this post as I collect more data and learn new things about the roaster.
Pricing If you want to buy a Nesco, you probably won’t have to buy it at full price ($80).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi Everyone! I’m Jason Yang, an Econ/Math grad from The University of Chicago. Currently, I work at Bridgewater Associates (a hedge fund) in the Futures and FX trade execution team.
I’ve produced some (probably definitely mediocre) research in Financial Economics as an Undergrad and follow articles published in top economics and finance research journals. I now roast and brew single origin coffees from around the world and spend an unhealthy amount of time thinking about personal finance and taxes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
