<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee on Jason&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/categories/coffee/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coffee on Jason&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 09:48:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/categories/coffee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Delayed 2022 Single Origin List</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coffeelist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/coffeelist/</guid>
      <description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to build my palate so I can identify differences across single origin coffees. So here&amp;rsquo;s my list so far:
 Colombia Brazil (Dry Process) Guatemala Huehuetenago / Antigua Burundi Ethiopia (Washed, Natural) Sumatra Peru India Bali Honduras  I pulled this list from some combination of Sweet Maria&amp;rsquo;s (a site that ships unroasted coffee) most popular list and the most common origins I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on coffee roaster websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I bought the Breville Dual Boiler</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/favoritecoffees_3_12_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/favoritecoffees_3_12_22/</guid>
      <description>These two points are more indicative of my personal preference and situation, more than anything else.
There were 2 main drivers for me:
 Consistency and ease of use Fast heat up time  Consistency and ease of use go hand in hand. The dial-in process requires a ton of time, effort, and (now increasingly expensive&amp;hellip;) coffee. Ideally, you dial-in like a science experiment - change one variable and evaluate the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Tasting between 3 Coffees</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_1_9_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/newbeans_1_9_22/</guid>
      <description>Since my Nesco roaster was recalled (funny story for another time), I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to own 3 different fresh(ish) coffees at once until just today.
Onto business - I tried 3 different coffees.
 Ethiopian Single Origin coffee from Shearwater Coffee in Westport, CT Highline Blend (a light roast blend, couldn&amp;rsquo;t find origin info) from Irving Farm in New York, NY Decaf Guatemala from Happy Mug in Edinboro, PA  I looked for the predominant flavor, finish, and texture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nesco Review</title>
      <link>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:48:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jasonyang5.github.io/public/post/nesco/</guid>
      <description>I got a great deal on a Nesco roaster ($45 for an open-box product, normally $80) and figured it would be great value at that price. I’ve used this roaster ~50 times, which should be enough to comment a bit on a very simple machine.
I’ll update this post as I collect more data and learn new things about the roaster.
Pricing If you want to buy a Nesco, you probably won’t have to buy it at full price ($80).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
